A Guide to the Southern Elections Fund & Julian Bond Papers 1965-1975
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
- SOUTHERN ELECTIONS FUND PAPERS
  - SUBSERIES B: OFFICE FILES
    - Correspondence: Early SEF 1968-1970 (Box 6)
    - Correspndence (Miscellaneous) 1973 Jan-Jun, 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Correspondence (Miscellaneous) 1973 Jul-1974, 2 folders (Box 7)
    - Financial Records: Citizens Trust Company receipts 1971-1972 (Box 7)
    - Financial Records: Invoices, Recepits, Bills paid 1973-1974 (Box 7)
    - Financial Records: New York and SEF 1971 (Box 7)
    - Financial Statements Report 1972 (Box 7)
    - Georgia Department of Family & Child Services: Minimum Standards for Group Day Care Services 1969 (Box 7)
    - Guide to the SEF's Personnel Policies and Procedures 1973, 2 copies (Box 7)
    - The Impact of the Tax Reform Act of 1969 On Active Social Welfare Organizations, with a letter to Antonio Harrison, SEF Director 1970 (Box 7)
    - Letters and Speech drafts 1973 (Box 7)
    - List of Georgians n.d. (Box 7)
    - Memoranda 1973 (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous Printed Material 1969-1975 (Box 2 folders)
    - Newsletters 1973-1974 (Box 8)
    - Photographs n.d., 3 photographs (Box 8)
    - Press Releases 1971-1975 (Box 8)
    - SEF Action Bulletin 1972-1973 (Box 8)
    - SEF Organizational Plan ca. 1969 (Box 8)
    - Telephone Log 1973 (Box 8)
  - SUBSERIES C: NAME FILES
    - Black Congressional Caucus 1971 (Box 8)
    - John Cashin, Chairman, National Democratic Party of Alabama 1971 (Box 8)
    - Center for Community Change 1971 (Box 8)
    - Center for Political Reform n.d. (Box 8)
    - Shirley Chisholm -- Presidential campaign 1972 (Box 8)
    - Citizens' Research Foundation n.d. (Box 8)
    - Concept Films, Inc. 1971 (Box 8)
    - John Conyers 1971 (Box 8)
    - Shirley W. Cooks 1971 (Box 8)
    - Creative Systems, Inc., Social Systems Division n.d. (Box 8)
    - Charlie Evers, mayor, Fayette, Mississippi 1973 (Box 8)
    - The Medgar Evers Fund, Inc. 1971 (Box 8)
    - FOCUS: Newsletter of the Joint Center for Political Studies 1972-1974 (Box 8)
    - Jated Green, Jr. n.d. (Box 8)
    - Martin Luther King Foundation 1973 (Box 8)
    - Law Students Civil Rights Research Council (Ben Peterson) 1973 (Box 8)
    - John Lewis, Voter Education Project 1971 (Box 8)
    - Medical Aid for Indochina, Inc. (Ken Coplon) 1973 (Box 8)
    - Charles Morgan, Jr., American Civil Liberties Union 1965 (Box 8)
    - NAACP Legal Defense Fund 1973 (Box 8)
    - National Priorities Alert 1973 (Box 8)
    - New England Committee for Nonviolent Action 1970 (Box 8)
    - Channing Phillips n.d. (Box 8)
    - John S. Saloma III, M.I.T. 1971 (Box 8)
    - Selma Inter-religious Project ( SIP Newsletter) 1970 (Box 8)
    - Southern Poverty Law Center 1973 (Box 8)
    - Voter Education Project 1969-1973 (Box 8)
    - Dae Walker: Dae, Palmer & Associates 1973 (Box 8)
    - Andrew Young: Atlanta Community Relations Committee 1970, 1975 (Box 8)
  - SUBSERIES D: FUND RAISING
    - Joseph P. Antonow 1973-1974 (Box 9)
    - Boulder Fund Raiser 1973 (Box 9)
    - Brandt Fund Raiser Garden Party (East Hampton Party, Summer 1970), with photographs of Julian Bond 1970 (Box 9)
    - California Lists 1973 (Box 9)
    - Century Club: Correspondence and Certificates 1973-1975 (Box 9)
    - Century Club: Letters to members 1973-1974 (Box 9)
    - Century Club: Roster and Mailings 1973-1974 (Box 9)
    - Change of Donor Addresses 1971-1974 (Box 9)
    - Chicago Fund Raiser 1974-1975 (Box 9)
    - Claudine: SEF reception and premiere 1974 (Box 9)
    - Columbia, South Carolina Fund Raiser 1973 (Box 9)
    - Contacts 1970-1971 (Box 9)
    - Contributions/Donations 1973 (Box 9)
    - Contributions from Black Elected Officials 1973 (Box 9)
    - Contributions from Unions 1973-1975 (Box 9)
    - Contribution Thank-yous 1970 (Box 9)
    - Corporation Appeals and Responses 1973-1974 (Box 9)
    - Correspondence re: List Exchanges 1973-1974 (Box 9)
    - CRF Listing of Political Contributions of $500 or more in 1968 1971 (Box 9)
    - Denver Fund Raiser 1973 (Box 9)
    - Des Moines Fund Raiser 1973 (Box 9)
    - Dinners 1970 (Box 10)
    - Direct Mail: Black Elected Officials Mailing Analyses 1974 (Box 10)
    - Direct Mail Fundraisers, Inc. 1973-1974 (Box 10)
    - Direct Mail: Letters and Reports 1971-1974 (Box 10)
    - Direct Mail: Lincoln Graphic Arts, Inc. 1973 (Box 10)
    - Direct Mail: Prices for supplies and suggestive lists 1973 (Box 10)
    - Direct Mail: Sample SEF enclosures 1973 (Box 10)
    - Direct Mail: Schneider and Rich Associates 1973-1974 (Box 10)
    - Direct Mailing Test: Upcoming Mailings 1973 (Box 10)
    - Donor Letters in response to mailings 1971-1976 (Box 10)
    - Donor Mailings 1975, n.d. (Box 10)
    - Donors of $100 and Over 1970-1975 (Box 10)
    - Donors of less than $100 n.d. (Box 10)
    - Don't Play Us Cheap: Invitation Letters 1973 Mar-Apr, 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Don't Play Us Cheap: Invoices, Photographs and Press Releases (Box 10)
    - Fiegen Fund Raising Party 1970 (Box 11)
    - Fund Appeals to SEF: Letters 1970-1971 (Box 11)
    - The Fund Raising Institute 1974 (Box 11)
    - Fund Raising (Form) Letters 1968, 1970-1975, n.d., 3 folders (Box 11)
    - Fund Raising Lists (Inactive) 1970 & 1972 (Box 11)
    - Fund Raising Material: California Physicians & Dentists 1968, n.d. (Box 11)
    - Fund Raising Material: California Trip 1971 (Box 11)
    - Fund Raising Miscellaneous 1970 & 1975, n.d. (Box 11)
    - Fund Raising Responses 1973-1975 (Box 11)
    - Fund Raising Seminars 1973 (Box 11)
    - Gary & Lee Hart Fundraising Reception 1973 (Box 11)
    - Hubert H. Humphrew: Fundraiser letter in support of SEF 1973 (Box 11)
    - Sen. Edward Kennedy Fundraiser Party: Addresses 1974 (Box 11)
    - Los Angeles Fund Raiser: Thank-you Letters 1973 (Box 11)
    - Mailing Lists 1970-1972, n.d., 4 folders (Box 12)
    - Mailing Lists: Albert & Miriam Ornstein to Yancey Martin 1973 (Box 12)
    - Mailing Lists: Political Associates 1973, n.d. (Box 12)
    - Maryland & Massachusetts Thank-yous 1972-1974 (Box 12)
    - Mobile, Alabama Thank-yous 1973 (Box 12)
    - New York Fund Raiser 1973 (Box 12)
    - Oakland & Oregon Thank-yous 1973 (Box 12)
    - Potential Donors n.d. (Box 12)
    - Princeton, New Jersey: Fundraising contacts 1970 (Box 12)
    - Rainbow Sign Luncheon (Berkeley, California): Thank-yous 1973 (Box 12)
    - Rap & Collins, Inc.: McGovern Donor List 1973 (Box 12)
    - Recording Sheets for SEF Contributions 1973-1974 (Box 12)
    - Howard Samuels Fund Raisers 1970-1971 (Box 12)
    - San Francisco & Seattle Contributions 1973-1974 (Box 12)
    - Sharecroppers Fund 1973-1974 (Box 12)
    - Southern Christian Leadership Conference 1973 (Box 12)
    - SEF Picnic, Rockville, Maryland 1971 (Box 12)
    - Sperry Party (San Francisco) Thank-yous 1973 (Box 12)
    - Stockton Thank-yous 1973 (Box 12)
    - Thousandaire Club Rosters & Letters 1973 (Box 12)
    - (Box 12)
  - SUBSERIES E: CAMPAIGNS & ELECTIONS
    - Alabama Corrupt Practices Law 1974 (Box 13)
    - Black Elected Officials/Voter Registration 1968-1970 (Box 13)
    - Candidates Funded by SEF 1968-1970, 1973 (Box 13)
    - Candidates not Funded by SEF 1969 (Box 13)
    - Democratic National Committee 1971-1974 (Box 13)
    - Democratic National Convention: Delegate Selection Process 1971-1972 (Box 13)
    - Democratic Policy Council 1971 (Box 13)
    - Election 1970: Arkansas, Black Candidates 1970 (Box 13)
    - Election 1970: Candidate Funding Requests 1970 (Box 13)
    - Election 1970: Miscellaneous 1970 (Box 13)
    - Election 1970: "Referendum '70" notebook 1970 (Box 13)
    - Election 1970: SEF Candidates 1970-1971 (Box 13)
    - Greene County, Alabama: Special & General Elections 1969-1970 (Box 13)
    - Joseph W. Mallisham, candidates, Associate Police Commissioner, Tuscaloosa, Alabama 1969 (Box 13)
    - National Roster of Black Elected Officials 1970 (Box 13)
    - New articles re: racial violence 1965-1968 (Box 13)
    - News Articles 1968-1974, n.d. (Box 14)
    - Political Campaigns: Miscellaneous 1969-1975 (Box 14)
    - Poll Watchers n.d. (Box 14)
    - William Ferguson Reid, member, Virginia House of Delegates 1969 (Box 14)
    - Bertha C. Scales, candidate, Orlando, Florida school board 1970 (Box 14)
    - Scrapbook: Southern Voting Districts 1965-1969 (Box 14)
    - Scrapbook: Civil Rights & Elections 1968-1969 (Box 14)
    - SEF Contributions to Louisiana Candidates 1971 (Box 14)
    - Southern Office Holders Questionnaires 1969 (Box 14)
    - "Volunteer": The Lifeline of a Campaign by Mello Cotton and John Szostak 1970 (Box 14)
    - Arthur W. Walls, candidate, Virginia House of Delegates, Arlington County 1969 (Box 14)
    - Ronald J. Walton, candidate, commissioner of revenue, Norfolk, Virginia 1969 (Box 14)
    - Rev. Charles H. Wilhite, candidate, county commissioner, Troup County, Georgia 1969 (Box 14)
    - Alabama & Arkansas 1970, 1974 & 1975 (Box 14)
    - Georgia 1973-1975 (Box 14)
    - Louisiana 1969 & 1975 (Box 15)
    - Mississippi 1975, 2 folders (Box 15)
    - Kentucky, North Carolina, South Carolina, Texas, Virginia 1970 & 1975 (Box 15)
    - (Box 15)
- SERIES III: MISCELLANEOUS
  . It contains ca. 92 slides, 1963-1968, of persons and events associated with the civil rights era such as Martin Luther King, Jr. and the Nobel Peace Prize, the March on Washington, Ku Klux Klan activities, school integration, and black Sheriff Tom Gilmore of Greene County, Alabama. A videotape of unidentified content is present but researchers should note that at present the University of Virginia Library does not possess a tape player that will enable viewing it. The remainder of this series' materials consist of donor index cards, computer print-outs, and oversized accounting records. 1
  1Another photograph of Gilmore appears in David R. Goldfield, Black, White, and Southern(Baton Rouge: Louisiana State University Press, 1990), photograph section following page 236.
  This series (Boxes 15-16) is arranged alphabetically and chronologically.
  - Slides: Civil Rights activities 1963-1968, 65 black & white slides (Box 15)
  - Slides: "Life Klan Story/Bruce Roberts/Charlotte" n.d. (Box 15)
  - Color slides (Box 15)
  - Slides: Sheriff Tom Gilmore, Greene County, Alabama n.d., 7 color slides (Box 15)
  - Videotape with unidentified contents n.d. (Box 15)
  - Index Cards: [SEF Contributors] 1970 & 1973 (Box 16)
  - Index Cards: [Names & Telephone Numbers] n.d. (Box 16)
  - Index Cards: Address cards by name n.d. (Box 16)
  - Address cards by state n.d. (Box 16)
  - Southern Elections Fund-Operations: Income, Expenditures 1971 Mar-1972 Dec, Green binder (Oversize S-26)
  - "House" -- August & Sept list of contributors 1971 (Oversize S-26)
  - "House List" 1971, 2 sheets (Oversize S-26)
  - "Mailings/Fund-raising -- Sept. 19, Oct, Nov. 9th" 1971-1972 (Oversize S-26)
  - "House List Returns -- Oct '70 Mailing" 1972-1973, Green binder (Oversize S-26)
  - "Master File [of donors/donations?] 1973 Dec 4, Computer printout of 185 sheets (Oversize S-26)
  - Computer printout of New York donors, pp. 47-74 n.d. (Oversize S-26)
  - C-2 "Political Donors of Large Sums" n.d. (Oversize S-26)
  - C-3 "Donors Supporting liberal appeals" n.d. (Oversize S-26)
  - C 5-1 "Freedom Contributors" n.d. (Oversize S-26)
  - C 5-2 "Politically aware donors" n.d. (Oversize S-26)
  - C 5-3 CORE n.d. (Oversize S-26)
  - C 5-4 "Involved Donors to a liberal cause" (Connecticut) n.d. (Oversize S-26)